<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" 
      xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" 
      xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
      xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
      version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Yuping Shao</title>
<link>https://yshao.github.io/mysite/reswork.html</link>
<atom:link href="https://yshao.github.io/mysite/reswork.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<description>Academic website of Yuping Shao</description>
<generator>quarto-1.2.269</generator>
<lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 04:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<item>
  <title>VISLab - Current Research</title>
  <dc:creator>Yuping Shao</dc:creator>
  <link>https://yshao.github.io/mysite/posts/current-research/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<section id="how-i-come-to-pointcloud-registration" class="level1">
<h1>How I come to pointcloud registration</h1>
<p>I’ve been working for many years, on a disciplined procedure for an integrative merging between biomedical data and deep learning. To address this, I’ve been working with my advisor @ WPI to solve the fundamental problems that exist in multimodal dataset as an abstraction.</p>
<p>Since data preprocessing and analysis could take up 85% of the time, we find this an area of opportunity for practical optimization. For heterogeneous, multi-modal data, this challenging and time-consuming task shares the fundamental problem - registration. A common and similar use-case is the navigation of autonomous vehicles, from which multi-modal datasets are plentiful and far less sparse and hence spurred much progress in computer vision methods for multi-modal data.</p>
<p>Pointcloud is an N-dimensional dataset to perform research in multi-variate and multi-dimensional optimization. The bulk of my research is optimization methods on the registration problem - concretely, to improve upon the non-convexity of corresponding low dimensions, ie. the observational views of data. Since registration is a fundamental problem, it will show improvement on any downstream problem with any dataset, ie. domain adaptation, score ranking, tracking, etc.</p>
<p>Hence, from here, I’m highly motivated to practical medical applications that could bring to data science the rigor of human reasoning and knowledge from the brain science/health science space.</p>
</section>
<section id="zero-shot-visual-recognition" class="level1">
<h1>Zero-shot visual recognition</h1>
<p>An area of immense interest is to connect the mechanisms that lead to safe and reliable machine learning/deep learning system. To this end, visual and semantics reasoning in the processing of the multi-modal representation is necessary for the compositionality of “objectness”. To exhibit robustness in this type of recognition system is the primary aim of zero-shot recognition.</p>
<p>Mathematically, the pointcloud registration could be considered as a visual representation of graphical relationships between neighborhoods, this leads to an interoperability between several mathematical frameworks between patch-based (pixel, voxel, lines) and graph-based (network, node/links graph, DAG) representations. Illustraing the a variety of forms and formulations of duality between patch and graph.</p>
<p>This duality makes it possible for variety of sampling assumptions to match between different sensor modalities. The matching depends on assumptions in regard to the modality. Hence, a rich area of possibilities that exist in building compositionality between the modalities based on sampling functions.</p>
</section>
<section id="research-topics-relates-to-optimization" class="level1">
<h1>Research topics relates to Optimization</h1>
<section id="optimization-techniques" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="optimization-techniques">Optimization techniques</h2>
<pre><code>Sparsity
Regularization</code></pre>
</section>
<section id="optimization-assumptions" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="optimization-assumptions">Optimization assumptions</h2>
<pre><code>Diffusion or the markov assumption
Prototypes or component analysis</code></pre>
</section>
</section>
<section id="application-topics-related-to-registration" class="level1">
<h1>Application topics related to registration</h1>
<section id="biomedical-imaging" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="biomedical-imaging">Biomedical imaging</h2>
<pre><code>Photo-acoustic medicine
Ultrasound</code></pre>
</section>
<section id="n-dimensional-signals" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="n-dimensional-signals">N-dimensional signals</h2>
<pre><code>multi-modal signals/sensor fusion
system-based synchronization</code></pre>


</section>
</section>

<div id="quarto-appendix" class="default"><section class="quarto-appendix-contents"><h2 class="anchored quarto-appendix-heading">Reuse</h2><div quarto-reuse="quarto-reuse" class="quarto-appendix-contents"><a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</a></div></section><section class="quarto-appendix-contents"><h2 class="anchored quarto-appendix-heading">Citation</h2><div><div class="quarto-appendix-secondary-label">BibTeX citation:</div><pre class="sourceCode code-with-copy quarto-appendix-bibtex"><code class="sourceCode bibtex">@online{shao2022,
  author = {Yuping Shao},
  title = {VISLab - {Current} {Research}},
  date = {2022-05-18},
  url = {https://yshao.github.io/mysite//posts/current-research},
  langid = {en}
}
</code></pre><div class="quarto-appendix-secondary-label">For attribution, please cite this work as:</div><div id="ref-shao2022" class="csl-entry quarto-appendix-citeas">
Yuping Shao. 2022. <span>“VISLab - Current Research.”</span> May 18,
2022. <a href="https://yshao.github.io/mysite//posts/current-research">https://yshao.github.io/mysite//posts/current-research</a>.
</div></div></section></div> ]]></description>
  <category>data science</category>
  <category>misc</category>
  <guid>https://yshao.github.io/mysite/posts/current-research/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Graduate (Master)</title>
  <dc:creator>Yuping Shao</dc:creator>
  <link>https://yshao.github.io/mysite/posts/graduate/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<section id="georgiatech-work-in-a-5-minutes-video" class="level1">
<h1>GeorgiaTech Work in a 5 minutes video</h1>
<p>I received my training in computer science through Georgia Tech while employed as a full-time embedded system designer and software engineer at Boulder Environment Sciences and Tech (BEST). The topics of health informatics and big data in healthcare would later bring me together with the researchers in neurology at MGH.</p>
<p>This video clip was prepared as part of Ph.D.&nbsp;application demo. <a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/15bq3rSjzFAH69RkQe0_An6muuSnkCzPw/edit">Video</a></p>
</section>
<section id="digital-porfolio-in-progress-of-update" class="level1">
<h1>Digital Porfolio (in progress of update…)</h1>
</section>
<section id="big-data-for-healthcare-analytics" class="level1">
<h1>Big Data for Healthcare Analytics</h1>
<p>MIMIC3 readmission prediction</p>
<p>This class introduced many big data analytics methods as applied to electronic health records processing. For the final thesis paper, I researched the topic of readmission to the hospital after discharge. I harvested the readmission labels from the MIMIC-3 database and then prepared features from patients’ vitals, labs, and demographics. The readmission label criterion looks for people who came back to the hospital within 30 days, essentially discharged while their inpatient health progression would indicate for a longer stay. The RNN (recurrent neural network) model with GRU was built in PyTorch, and then again in TensorFlow. It achieved an AUROC of 71%. Though being a black box, it was not interpretable. From this project, I learned the importance of interpretability to make the model useful for advancing the understanding of healthcare science.</p>
<p><a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1T1iScfGKjeD0UIlGQAVlkLCwoK87f8rX/view">Report</a></p>
</section>
<section id="computational-photography" class="level1">
<h1>Computational Photography</h1>
<p>Cartoonize Me This is a fun class. After learning the basics of computer vision, this class uses the OpenCV and other image processing libraries to create effects on photos and videos. I also learned how to use an SLR camera, which is not easy to get right.</p>
<p><a href="https://github.com/yshao/streaming_stylized_video">Demo</a></p>
<p><a href="">Slides</a></p>
</section>
<section id="healthcare-informatics" class="level1">
<h1>Healthcare Informatics</h1>
<p>This class introduced me to one of the components of cognitive reasoning - bayesian trees/nets. It’s a team project to stream the FHIR informatics to a zikas virus detection web app. The algorithm part I implemented is a simple bayesian network based on risk factors of the patient’s medical history.</p>
<p><a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/13xuuSkeBxm2p_4a6xcEwcivEBSPGTnGk/view">Slides</a></p>
</section>
<section id="human-computer-interface" class="level1">
<h1>Human Computer Interface</h1>
<p>This is a design class that involves designing interactivity - in terms of cognition, communication, and computing device, and where interface could exist. Part design, part philosophical. Part architectural design, part survey work. Half individual, half group work.</p>
<p>Our team designed a paper for an app using the principles from the class and designs a mobile-app that encourages adherence to a healthy lifestyle.</p>
<p><a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1PkckABymcfSszvvqxs5EkAEuGiRnkQX2/view">Report</a></p>
</section>
<section id="educational-technology" class="level1">
<h1>Educational Technology</h1>
<p>Project KnowledgeCog</p>
<p>With this project, I worked with an assigned advisor in the Educational Technology class to do independent research. I set out to research the methodology for building an intelligent tutor agent that could understand works of fiction and then assess and evaluate human users on their understanding of the readings. The agent utilizes NLP (natural language processing) to produce an auto-generated summary of paragraphs and link the sections of paragraphs as ordered concepts. The agent then presents the paragraphs to human users in order for them to put the paragraphs in order. From this activity, the agent assesses and evaluates the understanding of the human user. My mentor a Microsoft research scientist encouraged me to submit the report to Learning@Scale. This is an open draft that has not yet been submitted.</p>
<p><a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1DXvbcIdjtE6hwXq_Jgcr6jyC0Txpy7zj/view">Report</a></p>
</section>
<section id="cognitive-system" class="level1">
<h1>Cognitive System</h1>
<p>Raven Progressive Matrices</p>
<p>The first class I took as part of GaTech’s master of computer science degree. Turns out the ideas discussed in the class are much more than this introductory class could cover in a semester. I think cognition-inspired computation is really where it’s at for computational sciences.</p>
<p>In this class, I built an agent to solve Raven Progressive Matrices, which is a human intelligence metric applied to measure AI intelligence.</p>
<p><a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1IMVuZRgeQUlw7P9NlDnSezzSjPO7ZLX2/view">Report</a></p>
</section>
<section id="computer-vision" class="level1">
<h1>Computer Vision</h1>
<p>Computer vision fundamentals</p>
<p>One of the first classes I took at GaTech. The instructor Aaron Bobick (currently a dean of engineering at Washington University) was just one of the greatest instructors at the institute. Really engaging instructor and pretty much like drinking from a firehose going through the class. The class covers fundamentals completely not including deep learning, hence would be considered “classical computer vision”</p>
</section>
<section id="machine-learning" class="level1">
<h1>Machine Learning</h1>
<p>WEKA, openai, R…, machine learning toolboxes</p>
<p>The first machine learning class I took as part of GaTech’s master of computer science degree. It covers all the categories of machine learning, supervised learning, randomized optimization, unsupervised learning, reinforcement learning..etc</p>
<p>I will find out later that there’s a self-, or semi-supervised learning that is a category of its own, too.</p>
<p>Wrote 4 reports, one report for each category. This class is like drinking from a hose with each report.</p>
<p><a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1kCm_3Uy_b4Zdyyr1hrSY_8QrWIHH5zcn/view">Report</a></p>
</section>
<section id="machine-learning-for-trading" class="level1">
<h1>Machine Learning for Trading</h1>
<p>Timeseries learning with robot</p>
<p>This class has timeseries, robots, and QLearning! (and Deep RL) There’s a section on financial stock background, and the rest of the class is about reading timeseries signals and apply data science and data modeling to do predictive analytics. A very practical class that introduced me to pandas.</p>
<p><a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1bSTDHMe4d8KtWeO54eO7D-ZaLcByv2uV/view">Report</a></p>


</section>

<div id="quarto-appendix" class="default"><section class="quarto-appendix-contents"><h2 class="anchored quarto-appendix-heading">Reuse</h2><div quarto-reuse="quarto-reuse" class="quarto-appendix-contents"><a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</a></div></section><section class="quarto-appendix-contents"><h2 class="anchored quarto-appendix-heading">Citation</h2><div><div class="quarto-appendix-secondary-label">BibTeX citation:</div><pre class="sourceCode code-with-copy quarto-appendix-bibtex"><code class="sourceCode bibtex">@online{shao2022,
  author = {Yuping Shao},
  title = {Graduate {(Master)}},
  date = {2022-05-18},
  url = {https://yshao.github.io/mysite//posts/graduate},
  langid = {en}
}
</code></pre><div class="quarto-appendix-secondary-label">For attribution, please cite this work as:</div><div id="ref-shao2022" class="csl-entry quarto-appendix-citeas">
Yuping Shao. 2022. <span>“Graduate (Master).”</span> May 18, 2022. <a href="https://yshao.github.io/mysite//posts/graduate">https://yshao.github.io/mysite//posts/graduate</a>.
</div></div></section></div> ]]></description>
  <category>data science</category>
  <category>misc</category>
  <guid>https://yshao.github.io/mysite/posts/graduate/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Neuroscience/Biomedical</title>
  <dc:creator>Yuping Shao</dc:creator>
  <link>https://yshao.github.io/mysite/posts/neuroscience/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<section id="algonauts-2021" class="level1">
<h1>Algonauts 2021</h1>
<p>Due to my tangential exposure to neuroscience during my work at neuro critical care and infectious disease control. The summer after I started my PhD in Spring 2021, I was consecutively a student in the Neuromatch Academy computational neuroscience track, and then also a mentor in my home institution data science/neuroscience research experience for undergraduates (REU). I skipped the consecutive Neuromatch Academy deep learning track cause a brain can only handle so much!</p>
<p>The team I was a mentor of researched a topic on building correspondence between what the eyes see and what the brain sense, which itself is based on the Algonauts 2021 challenge. The overall ambitious goal was to link between multi-modal dataset.</p>
<p><a href="http://algonauts.csail.mit.edu/challenge.html">Website</a></p>
<p>They won the poster award at Undergraduate Research Technology Conference (URTC 2021)! It was a great experience overall. I believe at least one of the students would go into Ph.D.&nbsp;program herself.</p>
<p><a href="https://urtc.mit.edu/">Website</a></p>
</section>
<section id="neuromatch-2021" class="level1">
<h1>Neuromatch 2021</h1>
<p>For my own computational track. I based my fMRI analysis on the Human Connectome Project (HPC). The work was done in collaboration with my neuromatch cohort that include researchers from Univ Virginia - A, WashU@St. Louis, MIT, Univ in Mexico City. This is a sample preliminary concept of an application. Research questions: “can we predict participants’ accuracy on the social animacy task from between and within network connectivity? can the prediction model improve its performance when resting-state-fMRI data is included?”</p>
</section>
<section id="wpi" class="level1">
<h1>@ WPI</h1>
<section id="ultrasound-imaging-and-other-modality-imaging." class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="ultrasound-imaging-and-other-modality-imaging.">Ultrasound Imaging and other modality imaging.</h2>
<p>Since I started at WPI at the peak of COVID in 2021. A lab specialized in photoacoustic medicine was interested in ultrasound based scan.</p>
<p>The class resulted in a imaging report using concept of co-segmention. I collaborated with fellow Ph.D.&nbsp;students from Robotics Engineering and Electrical Computer Engineering.</p>
<p><a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1xt-ak_X6XyyZ5AQFsjA8USIUW_u8jsz4/view">Report</a></p>
</section>
<section id="multimodal-brain-computer-interface." class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="multimodal-brain-computer-interface.">Multimodal brain computer interface.</h2>
<p>The class is a seminar on brain computer interfaces, and included concepts from early development, clinical usage like stroke, human computer interfaces AR/VR, and other biosignals.</p>
<p>I researched in the interface to sense potential factors contribute to thresholds of good judgment. <a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1xt-ak_X6XyyZ5AQFsjA8USIUW_u8jsz4/view">Report</a></p>


</section>
</section>

<div id="quarto-appendix" class="default"><section class="quarto-appendix-contents"><h2 class="anchored quarto-appendix-heading">Reuse</h2><div quarto-reuse="quarto-reuse" class="quarto-appendix-contents"><a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</a></div></section><section class="quarto-appendix-contents"><h2 class="anchored quarto-appendix-heading">Citation</h2><div><div class="quarto-appendix-secondary-label">BibTeX citation:</div><pre class="sourceCode code-with-copy quarto-appendix-bibtex"><code class="sourceCode bibtex">@online{shao2022,
  author = {Yuping Shao},
  title = {Neuroscience/Biomedical},
  date = {2022-05-18},
  url = {https://yshao.github.io/mysite//posts/neuroscience},
  langid = {en}
}
</code></pre><div class="quarto-appendix-secondary-label">For attribution, please cite this work as:</div><div id="ref-shao2022" class="csl-entry quarto-appendix-citeas">
Yuping Shao. 2022. <span>“Neuroscience/Biomedical.”</span> May 18, 2022.
<a href="https://yshao.github.io/mysite//posts/neuroscience">https://yshao.github.io/mysite//posts/neuroscience</a>.
</div></div></section></div> ]]></description>
  <category>data science</category>
  <category>misc</category>
  <guid>https://yshao.github.io/mysite/posts/neuroscience/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Undergraduate</title>
  <dc:creator>Yuping Shao</dc:creator>
  <link>https://yshao.github.io/mysite/posts/undergraduate/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<section id="nanotech-optics-and-robotics" class="level1">
<h1>Nanotech, Optics and Robotics</h1>
<p>In my undergraduate, I was interested in everything nano, optical, abstract invariant principles of the physical world. The “goal project” was creating self-assemblying nano-fabricators. The possibilities at creating a abundance society appealed to me.</p>
<p>I had the fortune to work with a nobel prize winner in nanometerials, Shuji Nakamura, the inventor of blue LED, that summer was both fun and informative, as I found out how “wet” work is conducted in a fab room. I learned about van de pauw method of Hall effect measurement and a bit of crystal lattice structure.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.nnin.org/sites/default/files/files/2005NNINreuShao.pdf">Paper</a></p>
<p>For my undergraduate design project. I invented a innovative apparatus and electrochemistry process to create material for the characterization of laser beam profile with high purity silver. (95% and above, grade above sterling silver, which is at ~93%)</p>
<p><a href="https://projects-web.engr.colostate.edu/ece-sr-design/AY06_07/erc_nano/YSHAO_senior_design.pdf">Paper</a></p>
<p>The silver helical target became part of the patent description in a laser characterization apparatus</p>
<p><a href="https://patents.justia.com/patent/7609816">Link</a></p>
<p>I was also a mentor in FIRST Robotics for Team 159 at Poudre High School. I was also a former participant in the robotics competition</p>
<p>It’s one of the formative influences that led to study engineering. We won the Chairman’s Award for profileration of STEM for the state of Colorado and was one of the early teams that made the presence significant for the FIRST committee to form the Colorado Regional.</p>
<p>I’ve learned most about robotics here. The open-source hardware movement later made it cool to use arduino and rasp-pi.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.firstinspires.org/robotics/frc">FIRST Website</a></p>
<p>On team 159, I did robot and motor controls, electronics and was the original webmaster. I learned also machine shop related skills with metal and plastic. The new website is much more organized today!</p>
<p><a href="https://alpinerobotics.org/">Team 159 Website</a></p>


</section>

<div id="quarto-appendix" class="default"><section class="quarto-appendix-contents"><h2 class="anchored quarto-appendix-heading">Reuse</h2><div quarto-reuse="quarto-reuse" class="quarto-appendix-contents"><a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</a></div></section><section class="quarto-appendix-contents"><h2 class="anchored quarto-appendix-heading">Citation</h2><div><div class="quarto-appendix-secondary-label">BibTeX citation:</div><pre class="sourceCode code-with-copy quarto-appendix-bibtex"><code class="sourceCode bibtex">@online{shao2022,
  author = {Yuping Shao},
  title = {Undergraduate},
  date = {2022-05-18},
  url = {https://yshao.github.io/mysite//posts/undergraduate},
  langid = {en}
}
</code></pre><div class="quarto-appendix-secondary-label">For attribution, please cite this work as:</div><div id="ref-shao2022" class="csl-entry quarto-appendix-citeas">
Yuping Shao. 2022. <span>“Undergraduate.”</span> May 18, 2022. <a href="https://yshao.github.io/mysite//posts/undergraduate">https://yshao.github.io/mysite//posts/undergraduate</a>.
</div></div></section></div> ]]></description>
  <category>data science</category>
  <category>misc</category>
  <guid>https://yshao.github.io/mysite/posts/undergraduate/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Work Experience in Colorado</title>
  <dc:creator>Yuping Shao</dc:creator>
  <link>https://yshao.github.io/mysite/posts/work-experience/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<section id="woodward" class="level1">
<h1>Woodward</h1>
<p>Right before I moved to Boulder, I had a gig working in the renewable energy initiative in 2008 on energy/gas/oil/wind turbine controllers. I worked on two different projects, Falcon and Eagle. One is for liquid valve controller, the other is for gas. The facility at Fort Collins is both the design center as well as the manucturing plant. The part I remember was it had a giant lathe that is more than 10 feet tall to machine the turbine controller in one piece</p>
<p><a href="https://www.woodward.com/en/shop/woodward44-gas-metering-and-shutoff">Website</a></p>
</section>
<section id="spectra-logic" class="level1">
<h1>Spectra Logic</h1>
<p>I took a database design course when I was a sustaining electrical engineer at a company that builds scalable deep storage controlled by robotics. The database built was for PCBA (printed circuit board assembly) quality control. Assemblies made from off the shelf parts often have nominal differences, and for as precise control as robotics, these nominal differences transform into unique offsets and calibration. I compiled a research paper before implementing some of the idea into the storage media certification process.</p>
<p><a href="">Report</a></p>
<p>The implementation of this automation infrastructure became a business unit at the company. For this role product improvments, I worked across 12 individual departments and had groups of technical personnels reporting to me. The role was to integrate all numerous autonomous sub-assemblies from mechanical/electrical/firmware/software/service into a production line.</p>
<p>The software/system integration I did would integrate the disk library product into a hybrid system with the tape library product - the main offering of the company. The many subparts of the integration work involved communication between the robotics and the communication and control main board of the tape library unit. Therefore, I was automating work on the CanBus and Ethernet switch, as well as making utilities for functional exercise of the motors, scaners, media readers, boot EEPROM, etc. <a href="https://spectralogic.com/products/spectra-t950/">Website</a></p>
</section>
<section id="radiometers-and-beyond" class="level1">
<h1>Radiometers and beyond</h1>
<p>Right before I moved to Boston, I worked at this place that builds miniaturized radiometer, a type of atmospheric sensing instrument, that in its aerial form factor, is 10-15 years ahead of its competitions. The website they run shows the amazing science this place do. The other form factors for remote sensing radiometer include land-based in antarctica. I worked only on the marine-buoy and the aerial instrument that was mounted on Unmanned aerial vehicles (UAVs).</p>
<p><a href="http://www.boulderest.com/">Website</a></p>
<p>The company apparently has moved to mostly satellites related sensing.</p>


</section>

<div id="quarto-appendix" class="default"><section class="quarto-appendix-contents"><h2 class="anchored quarto-appendix-heading">Reuse</h2><div quarto-reuse="quarto-reuse" class="quarto-appendix-contents"><a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</a></div></section><section class="quarto-appendix-contents"><h2 class="anchored quarto-appendix-heading">Citation</h2><div><div class="quarto-appendix-secondary-label">BibTeX citation:</div><pre class="sourceCode code-with-copy quarto-appendix-bibtex"><code class="sourceCode bibtex">@online{shao2022,
  author = {Yuping Shao},
  title = {Work {Experience} in {Colorado}},
  date = {2022-05-18},
  url = {https://yshao.github.io/mysite//posts/work-experience},
  langid = {en}
}
</code></pre><div class="quarto-appendix-secondary-label">For attribution, please cite this work as:</div><div id="ref-shao2022" class="csl-entry quarto-appendix-citeas">
Yuping Shao. 2022. <span>“Work Experience in Colorado.”</span> May 18,
2022. <a href="https://yshao.github.io/mysite//posts/work-experience">https://yshao.github.io/mysite//posts/work-experience</a>.
</div></div></section></div> ]]></description>
  <category>data science</category>
  <category>misc</category>
  <guid>https://yshao.github.io/mysite/posts/work-experience/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Work Experience in Massachusetts</title>
  <dc:creator>Yuping Shao</dc:creator>
  <link>https://yshao.github.io/mysite/posts/work-experience-boston/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<section id="clinical-data-animation-center---mgh" class="level1">
<h1>Clinical Data Animation Center - MGH</h1>
<p>I worked at Mass General Hospital Neurology Department in a clinical data analytics group (CDAC - clinical data animation center) with PI neurologist Dr.&nbsp;Brandon Westover where neurophysiology/computational neuroscience/clinical science intersect. Working at CDAC gave me the opportunity to interact with physicians, postdocs, and biomedical analysts with specialized knowledge of the dynamical system of human brain physiology. Find machine learning/deep learning models that work well, it involves the curation of data to get concept representations learned from clinical data, forming a database of metadata. This compositional data concept system can be harnessed to build machine learning algorithms for many detection and prediction of degenerative states of the brain physiology and medical informatics. My typical projects involve wrangling multimodal data source ranging from waveforms like EEG/EKG, clinical timeseries like labs/vitals, sequentially updated physician notes, and preparing them into research-ready data through data cleaning, interrogating data statistics, rule-based label harvesting, data pattern classification with models, and discovering data correlation through predictive modeling and data exploration. Projects I have been involved in include but are not limited to - Prediction of the onset of sepsis with streaming electronic health records. - Large-scale visualization of Spatio-temporal patterns from seizure burden data. - Delirium predictive analytics on electronic health records. - Big data analytics on EEG processing. - Automated Surveillance for Ventilator-Associated Events.</p>
<p>Professional data science competition include this one <a href="https://education.dellemc.com/content/dam/dell-emc/documents/en-us/2018KS_Tony-EEG_Report_to_Recordings_Matching_and_Text_Mining.pdf">EEG Report to Recordings Matching and Text Mining</a></p>
<section id="large-scale-tsne-map" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="large-scale-tsne-map">Large Scale tSNE Map</h2>
<p>Working at MGH is such an extraordinary opportunity. The CDAC group has what would be the largest database of EEG showing interesting seizure patterns. A book that was published based on this work is now on Amazon Book</p>
<p>The earliest attempt to curate 100 patients was pretty challenging, since there’s a lot of data variabilities. Data reduction and dimensional reduction techniques were needed to just get to the clustering stage for unsupervised learning.</p>
<p>The 2nd stage became a semi-supervised learning project with improved approaches to curate data. Still, data volume made the project hard. In the second, the features seem to have been over-engineered and constrained. The parametric approach is learned network inference and hard to get right since the map is keep changing on a large-scale.</p>
<p><a href="https://cdac.mgh.harvard.edu/">Website</a></p>
</section>
<section id="sepsis-onset-detection" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="sepsis-onset-detection">Sepsis-onset Detection</h2>
<p>time-sensitive detection for near-time application</p>
<p>Predictive algorithm becomes policy relevant what it’s also predicting the onset, not just the category. This makes it relevant for interventional study.</p>
<p>This collaboration investigates the deployment of sepsis onset detection within ICU. Sepsis is a common precursor to neurological disorders. The early detection of its onset could provide opportunity for intervention within ICU healthcare.</p>
<p>To train the deep learning algorithm for the detection, I prepared a cohort of 7800 patients found within ICU with sepsis condition as determined by the Sepsis-III definition published by the Center for Disease Control (CDC). Then working with the clinical informatics group at Emory to develop a model that predicts the onset of sepsis.</p>
<p>The project introduces the importance of temporal context. For example, antibiotics medications are frequently given to patients within ICU, however, if antibiotics are given with certain number of times over 3 days when followed by microbiology culture test, then the medication was for sepsis treatment.</p>
<p><a href="https://drive.hhs.gov/solvingsepsis.html">Website</a></p>
</section>
<section id="cdac-workshops" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="cdac-workshops">CDAC Workshops</h2>
<p>I was a organizer and main work leader in a series of workshop to introduce clinical researchers to big data analytics workflow. Work was in collaboration with Manohar Ghanta and Moura Valdery whom was a brain health contributor at the time.</p>
<p>sanitized (deidentification applied) <a href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1Q45tsaPYzTDs5cW3FkX26OkkuiA3K9Nq/edit?usp=sharing&amp;ouid=101489133791778609187&amp;rtpof=true&amp;sd=true">Big Data Analytics Workshop</a></p>
<p><a href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1rz72LBZZ-gt_CGk_8IS4G-8DXar4lXB1/edit?usp=share_link&amp;ouid=101489133791778609187&amp;rtpof=true&amp;sd=true">Workshop 1</a></p>
<p><a href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/18sAd609dcV48GYIAIEScjqAzYt0krWNj/edit?usp=share_link&amp;ouid=101489133791778609187&amp;rtpof=true&amp;sd=true">Workshop 2</a></p>
<p><a href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1xdbfzSNvm_Y2xBrqVdqnfCEgx3JenC6I/edit?usp=share_link&amp;ouid=101489133791778609187&amp;rtpof=true&amp;sd=true">Workshop 3</a></p>
<p><a href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1RtFQRULnNA54MfntCrWerUsOdkLsC2nz/edit?usp=share_link&amp;ouid=101489133791778609187&amp;rtpof=true&amp;sd=true">Workshop 4</a></p>


</section>
</section>

<div id="quarto-appendix" class="default"><section class="quarto-appendix-contents"><h2 class="anchored quarto-appendix-heading">Reuse</h2><div quarto-reuse="quarto-reuse" class="quarto-appendix-contents"><a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</a></div></section><section class="quarto-appendix-contents"><h2 class="anchored quarto-appendix-heading">Citation</h2><div><div class="quarto-appendix-secondary-label">BibTeX citation:</div><pre class="sourceCode code-with-copy quarto-appendix-bibtex"><code class="sourceCode bibtex">@online{shao2022,
  author = {Yuping Shao},
  title = {Work {Experience} in {Massachusetts}},
  date = {2022-05-18},
  url = {https://yshao.github.io/mysite//posts/work-experience-boston},
  langid = {en}
}
</code></pre><div class="quarto-appendix-secondary-label">For attribution, please cite this work as:</div><div id="ref-shao2022" class="csl-entry quarto-appendix-citeas">
Yuping Shao. 2022. <span>“Work Experience in Massachusetts.”</span> May
18, 2022. <a href="https://yshao.github.io/mysite//posts/work-experience-boston">https://yshao.github.io/mysite//posts/work-experience-boston</a>.
</div></div></section></div> ]]></description>
  <category>data science</category>
  <category>misc</category>
  <guid>https://yshao.github.io/mysite/posts/work-experience-boston/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
